<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Initiative &#8211; DataScientia</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/initiative/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>DataScientia Initiative website</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 13:32:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/cropped-kidf-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Initiative &#8211; DataScientia</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>WENET &#8211; DIVERSITY IS KEY FOR NEW, AI-BASED SOCIAL MEDIA PLATFORM</title>
		<link>/wenet-diversity-is-key-for-new-ai-based-social-media-platform/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 08:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Initiative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wenet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=22131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Horizon 2020 funded WeNet research project officially started in January with a kick-off meeting in snowy Trento, Italy. WeNet is a multidisciplinary project– using computer science, sociology and engineering – that will create a platform that enables people to &#8230; ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="22131" class="elementor elementor-22131">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9992fe6 e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="9992fe6" data-element_type="container">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-b396f3c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="b396f3c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.23.0 - 25-07-2024 */
.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-stacked .elementor-drop-cap{background-color:#69727d;color:#fff}.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-framed .elementor-drop-cap{color:#69727d;border:3px solid;background-color:transparent}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap{margin-top:8px}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap-letter{width:1em;height:1em}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap{float:left;text-align:center;line-height:1;font-size:50px}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap-letter{display:inline-block}</style>				<p>The Horizon 2020 funded WeNet research project officially started in January with a kick-off meeting in snowy Trento, Italy. WeNet is a multidisciplinary project– using computer science, sociology and engineering – that will create a platform that enables people to support each other in a way that transcends geographical and cultural backgrounds. Diversity is a key enabler of the WeNet platform. It will use machine-learning algorithms to build user-profiles based on behavior and other key factors. The profiles will then be matched to positively exploit the diversity of users, allowing them to help one another. By connecting people from diverse backgrounds and skillsets, WeNet will enable them to interact and incentivize them to assist one another in ways that would not formerly have been possible. The WeNet platform will be the basis of a series of studies within universities worldwide with diverse student populations to improve students&#8217; quality of life inside and outside the academic environment, taking into consideration ethical and privacy guidelines. WeNet will start with a number of Smart University pilots to exploit diversity case studies. These will be extended by further engaging 5 new pilot sites that will be found via the Open Call funding system. For ensuring the long-term sustainability of the research infrastructure, a non-profit organization will be created, which will be in charge of managing the infrastructure and managing the community. This highly skilled consortium, led by the University of Trento, is composed of 15 partners from Europe and Israel, India, Mongolia, Paraguay, Mexico and China. The complementarity of the consortium partners is one of the greatest added values of WeNet, which includes highly rated universities and SMEs.</p><p><button>Download press release</button></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Not-for-profit cause launched for studying language diversity using artificial intelligence</title>
		<link>/not-for-profit-cause-launched-for-studying-language-diversity-using-artificial-intelligence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 08:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Initiative]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=22152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Led by the University of Trento in Northern Italy, in collaboration with six other partner institutions from Europe, China, India, Mongolia, Mexico, South Africa and South America, researchers from these institutions have announced the launch of the new initiative DataScientia &#8230; ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="22152" class="elementor elementor-22152">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-d939b28 e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="d939b28" data-element_type="container">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-96701e6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="96701e6" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Led by the University of Trento in Northern Italy, in collaboration with six other partner institutions from Europe, China, India, Mongolia, Mexico, South Africa and South America, researchers from these institutions have announced the launch of the new initiative DataScientia aiming at studying and connecting the diversity and unity of the world’s languages, with a special focus of under-resourced languages. The consortium of founding members includes Italy’s University of Trento, the National University of Mongolia, India’s Amrita University, China’s Jilin University, Paraguay’s Catholic University “Nuestra Señora de la Asunción”, South Africa’s Tshwane University of Technology, and UK’s Heriot-Watt University. The consortium will be working on several world languages including Italian, Gaelic, Spanish, Tamil, Malayalam, Hindi, African, Guarani and Mongolian. The workshop detailing this multi-community and multi-disciplinary project, held on January 29-30, 2019 at Trento, Italy, covered various enabling disciplines and technologies ranging from Artificial Intelligence and Computational Linguistics to linguistics, philosophy and social sciences.The DataScientia consortium has already set up projects for the development of various systems, among them: the Universal Knowledge Core (UKC) which allows the integration of the lexicons of the languages used to describe the world as perceived by the various cultures and languages, an engine for corpora collection, the SCROLL framework for multilingual Natural Language Processing, the data integration platform Digital University and a service provision platform based on behavioural patterns called Smart University.Prof. Fausto Giunchiglia from the University of Trento, who started this initiative, said: “This is a very important event which lays the basis for a new generation of research initiatives. The development of a single multilingual resource which integrates the world languages, its evolution in time, and its use for the study of the diversity and unity of languages, can be done meaningfully only with the participation of the people and Universities coming from and representing the relevant cultures. To succeed, we must develop this initiative as a win-win project where everybody brings their own culture and gets back the knowledge of how it relates to that of the others.” The consortium aim is to create a non-profit organisation which will ensure the long term sustainability of the project. While doing this, it will also engage and partner with many other University and groups for furthering this unity through diversity initiative.</p><p><button>Download press release</button></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AfriKiD workshop &#8211; Pretoria</title>
		<link>/afrikid-workshop-pretoria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Initiative]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=22257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We organized our first AfriKiD workshop with a motto &#8220;Unity and Diversity&#8221;.  The event was organized by the Tshwane University of Technology. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="22257" class="elementor elementor-22257">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-7df7854 e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="7df7854" data-element_type="container">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55bbe11 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55bbe11" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>We organized our first AfriKiD workshop with a motto &#8220;Unity and Diversity&#8221;.  The event was organized by the Tshwane University of Technology. </p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
